<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A commission and instructions to Charles Fleetwood, esq; Lieutenant General of the Army in Ireland, Edmund Ludlow, esq; Lieutenant General of the horse, Miles Corbet, esq; Iohn Iones, esq; impowering them to cause all the lands (therein mentioned to be forfeited to the Commonwealth) to be forthwith surveyed, in order to the satisfying of adventurers for Ireland, and arrears of officers and souldiers, and for the settling and planting of Ireland, with security to the inhabitants, and such as shall plant the same. Wednesday June 29. 1653. At the Councill of State at White-Hall, ordered, that this declartion be forthwith printed and published. John Thurloe Secr.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Council of State.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A84457</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99868486</idno>
  <idno type="VID">169141</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240969639</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E772A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1062_3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R209620</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99868486</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99868486e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A84457)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169141)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 158:E1062[3])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A commission and instructions to Charles Fleetwood, esq; Lieutenant General of the Army in Ireland, Edmund Ludlow, esq; Lieutenant General of the horse, Miles Corbet, esq; Iohn Iones, esq; impowering them to cause all the lands (therein mentioned to be forfeited to the Commonwealth) to be forthwith surveyed, in order to the satisfying of adventurers for Ireland, and arrears of officers and souldiers, and for the settling and planting of Ireland, with security to the inhabitants, and such as shall plant the same. Wednesday June 29. 1653. At the Councill of State at White-Hall, ordered, that this declartion be forthwith printed and published. John Thurloe Secr.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Council of State.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 21, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Giles Calvert, Thomas Brewster, and by and for Hen. Hills, and are to be sold at the Black-Spread-Eagle at the West end of Pauls, and at the Three Bibles in Pauls Church yard,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCLIII. [1653]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Land grants --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Surveying --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:169141:1"/>
            <p>A COMMISSION AND INSTRUCTIONS To <hi>Charles Fleetwood,</hi> Esq; Lieutenant General of the Army in <hi>Ireland, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mund Ludlow,</hi> Esq; Lieutenant Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral of the Horse, <hi>Miles Corbet,</hi> Esq; <hi>Iohn Iones,</hi> Esq; Impowering them to cause all the Lands (therein men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned to be forfeited to the Commonwealth) to be forthwith surveyed, in order to the satisfying of Adventurers for Ireland, and arrears of Officers and Souldiers, And for the settling and planting of <hi>Ireland,</hi> with security to the Inhabitants, and such as shall plant the same.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>coat of arms of the Protectorate</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="order_to_print">
                        <opener>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>
                                 <hi>Wednesday June</hi> 29. 1653.</date>
                           </dateline>
                        </opener>
                        <p>At the Councill of State at White-Hall, Ordered, that this Declaration be forthwith print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and published.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>
                              <hi>John Thurloe</hi> Secr.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Giles Calvert, Thomas Brewster,</hi> and by and for <hi>Hen. Hills,</hi> and are to be sold at the <hi>Black-Spread-Eagle</hi> at the West end of <hi>Pauls,</hi> and at the <hi>Three Bibles</hi> in <hi>Pauls</hi> Church yard, MDCLIII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="commission">
            <pb facs="tcp:169141:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:169141:2"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>coat of arms of the Protectorate</figDesc>
               </figure>The Keepers of the Liberties of <hi>England,</hi> by Authority of <hi>Parliament,</hi> To our Trusty and VVell-beloved, <hi>Charles Fleetwood,</hi> Esq; Lieutenant General of the Army in <hi>Ireland, Edmund Ludlow,</hi> Esq; Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant General of the Horse, <hi>Miles Corbet,</hi> Esq; and <hi>Iohn Iones,</hi> Esq;</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">G</seg>Reeting, Whereas since the beginning of the late horrid Rebellion in <hi>Ireland</hi> in the year one thousand six hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred fourty and one, four severall Acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment have been made for the incouragement of well-affected persons, Bodies Politique and Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate, to pay in divers considerable sums of mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney by way of Adventure, towards the Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pression of the said Rebellion, That is to say,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:169141:3"/> one Act entituled, <hi>An Act for the speedy and effectual reducing of the Rebels, in his Maiesties King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome of</hi> Ireland, <hi>to their due obedience to his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sty, and the Crown of</hi> England; And one other Act entituled, <hi>An Act for adding unto, and explaining of certain clauses in another Act made this Parliament, entituled, An Act for the speedy and effectual reducing of the Rebels, in his Majesties Kingdome of</hi> Ireland, <hi>to their due obedience to his Maiestie, and the Crowne of</hi> England; And one other Act entituled, <hi>An Act to enable Corporations, and bodies politique, to partici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pate of the benefit of an Act lately passed, entituled, an Act for the speedy and effectual reducing of the Rebells, in his Majesties Kingdome of</hi> Ireland, <hi>to their due obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience to his Majestie, and the Crown of</hi> England; And one other Act, entituled, <hi>an Act for the further advancement of an effectual &amp; speedy reduction of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bells in</hi> Ireland, <hi>to the obedience of his Maiesty, and the Crown of</hi> England. And whereas since the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of the said four Acts, one Ordinance was also made, entituled, <hi>an Ordinance or Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, for the encouragement of the Adventurers to make new subscriptions for Towns, Cities, and lands in</hi> Ireland; and likewise another Ordinance, of the thirtieth of <hi>November,</hi> one thousand six hundred fourty and seven; Vpon which seve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Acts and Ordinances, great sums of money have been subscribed, And paid in to the respec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Treasurers therein named, which by the said Acts and Ordinances are to be satisfied by severall proportions of the Lands of the Rebels aforesaid. And whereas also several great sums of money are grown due and in arrear as well unto the Officers and Souldiers, who have been imployed in reducing the said Rebells, as
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:169141:3"/> which have been lent, advanced, or are grown due for Arms, Ammunition, Provisions, and other supplies for that service.</p>
            <p>And whereas it is declared that the said Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels are subdued, and that the Rebellion in <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> is appeased and ended, to the end that satis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction may be made unto the Adventurers, Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, Souldiers, and other persons aforesaid, as soon as possible may be; and that Country of <hi>Ireland</hi> planted, and settled with security unto the Inhabitants and such as shall plant the same; We reposing trust and confidence in your care and faithfulnesse, have constituted, ordain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and appointed, and by these presents do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stitute, ordain and appoint you, our Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners, giving and granting unto you, or any two or more of you, full power and authority, in pursuance of the said Acts and Ordinances, to put in execution all and every the Instructions here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto annexed, for the exact and perfect Survey and Admesurement of all and every the Honors, Baronies, Castles, Mannours, Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, and Hereditaments, forfeited by force or vertue of all, or any of the sad Acts; and also of all, and every the Honours, Baronies, Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, Mannours, Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, belonging to the Crown of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> in the year one thousand six hundred and thirty, or any time since or late belonging to any Arch-Bishop, Bishop, Dean, Dean and Chapter, or other Officer belonging to that Hierarchy in right of the Arch-Bishoprick, Deanery, or other office aforesaid.</p>
            <p>And we do further hereby give power and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority to you, our said Commissioners, or two, or more of you, to nominate &amp; appoint such fit and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:169141:4"/> Persons to be Surveyors General, and also to approve of or reject, as you shall find cause, such Person, and Persons, as shall be nominated unto you by the said Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors General, to be employed as Surveyors under them for the purposes aforesaid; and to constitute and appoint a fit Person of Integri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Ability (for such an Imployment) to be Register for the said Lands, to execute and perform the office of Register according to the Instructions aforesaid, so far as the same con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern the Register.</p>
            <p>And we do hereby further authorize you, our said Commissioners, or any two or more of you, to administer unto all and every the said Surveyors General, Register, Deputy Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gister, and Vnder Surveyors, before they en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter upon the execution of their respective places, the Oath and Oaths respectively in and by the said Instructions appointed to be administred; and to administer an Oath in such other Cases as are hereby appointed; and to appoint such and so many Clerks and other Officers only, as shall be necessary for the speedy perfecting the said Work; and to give your Warrant, and Warrants, for payment, from time to time, of such moneys as shall be payable unto them, and every of them, for their respective Salle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, out of the forfeited Lands, or publique Revenues of <hi>Ireland, &amp;c.</hi> in such manner, as by the said Instructions is appointed: and to do, or cause to be done, all and every other Act, and Acts, thing, and things, directed by, or contained in, the said Instructions. Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse our selves at <hi>Westminster, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="instructions">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:169141:4"/>
            <head>INSTRVCTIONS for <hi>Charles Fleetwood,</hi> Esq; Lieutenant General of the Army in <hi>Ireland, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mund Ludlow,</hi> Esq; Lieutenant General of the Horse, <hi>Miles Corbet,</hi> Esq; and <hi>Iohn Iones,</hi> Esq; Commissioners autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rized by a Commission under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> for the purposes men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in the said Commission.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">Y</seg>OV shall, immediately up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the receipt of this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission, cause Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to be made in every County of <hi>Ireland,</hi> so as the same may be Fourty daies at the least before the setting forth of any the Lands in the said Commission intended, to this effect, <hi>viz.</hi> That every Person, or the Heirs, Executors, or Assigns of such Person, who on the twentie third day of <hi>October,</hi> in the year one thousand six hundred fourty and one, had a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny lawful Right, Title, or Interest, in, or out of any of the Lands of any of the Rebells in Ireland, or any the Lands forfeit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Acts of Parliament in the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission specifyed, lying within the County where any such Proclamation shall be made, shall, within twenty daies after the said Proclamati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:169141:5"/> shall be made in the said County, enter his and their Claim to the same, before such Persons as shall be Authorized by you to receive, hear, and determine the said Claims.</p>
            <p>You shall forthwith appoint such Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners as you shall think fit, and shall authorize them to receive all and every such Claim and Claims as shall be made in pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suance of the Proclamation aforesaid by the time therein limitted, and to cause the same to be entred by such Register as you shall appoint for that purpose, and immediate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly after the entry of such Claims to proceed in examining and determining the same, and that they cause a Copy of such Determi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation under their hands, or so many of them as you shall appoint, to be sent unto the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gister for the said forfeited Lands, to be by him Annexed to the Survey of those Lands touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing which such Claim shall be made.</p>
            <p>You shall cause to be Surveyed all the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours, Baronies, Castles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, of, or late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly belonging to all and every the Rebels of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and all the Lands forfeited by vertue or force of the several Acts of Parliament in the said Commission expressed, or any of them, lying or being within all and every the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinces of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and all the Meadow, Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ravle and Profitable Pasture belonging to each of the said Honours, Baronies, Castles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements respectively to be Admeasured and set forth, so as the same may be certainly, and distinctly known from
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:169141:5"/> other the Lands there, by their Qualities, Quantities, Names, Situation, Parish, or Place where the same do ly, with their Meets and Bounds; the Boggs, Woods, and bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren Mountains belonging to the respective Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>misses being mentioned in such Survey respec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tively, but not admeasured.</p>
            <p>You shall give Instructions to the Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors General, and the Surveyors to be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed under them, in the first Place to survey, Admeasure, and set forth, all and every such of the said forfeited Lands and Premisses as shall ly and be within the respective Counties of <hi>Limerick, Tipperary,</hi> and <hi>Waterford,</hi> in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince of <hi>Munster;</hi> the Kings County, the Queens County, the Counties of <hi>Eastmeath</hi> and <hi>Westmeath,</hi> in the Province of <hi>Lemster;</hi> the Counties of <hi>Down, Antrim,</hi> and <hi>Armagh,</hi> in the Province of <hi>Ulster;</hi> and to divide all the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited Lands, Meadow, Arable and profita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Pasture, with the Woods and Boggs, and barren Mountains thereunto respectively belonging, in each of the said Counties (except the Baronies of <hi>Dulick,</hi> and <hi>Slane,</hi> in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie of <hi>Eastmeath</hi>) into two equal Moities dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinguished and bounded each from the other, which division so made the Surveyors shall return by themselves apart unto you, mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning onely in grosse, what Honours, Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, Castles, Lands, Tenements and Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments each Moity did contain.</p>
            <p>You shall likewise give Instructions to the said Surveyors General, and the Vnder-Surveyors, that in the next place after the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:169141:6"/> Surveying and Admeasurement of the said Premisses in the Ten Counties aforesaid, they do Survey, Admeasure, and set forth all and every such of the said forfeited Lands and Premisses as shall ly within the Countie of <hi>Lowth</hi> in the <hi>Province</hi> of <hi>Vlster,</hi> in such sort as they are appointed to Survey, Admeasure, and set forth the forfeited Lands in the said Ten Counties, and to return the Surveys thereof as soon as the same shall be perfect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</p>
            <p>You shall Authorize and Appoint the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors General to present unto you from time to time, the names of such fit and able persons, who shall be well skilled in the Art of Surveying, as shall be necessary for the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veying and Admeasurement of the lands and Premisses aforesaid, and to appoint by War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant under their Hands and Seals such and so many of them as you shall approve of and think fit to be Surveyors under them, and to allow unto each of them such allowances as the said Surveyors General shall think fit and necessary for carrying on the said work of Surveying and measuring the Premisses as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, not exceeding three pounds for every thousand Acres.</p>
            <p>The said Surveyors General shall take a due Accompt that the said Vnder-Surveyors discharge their respective duties in this service, and in case of neglect or unfaithfulnesse in any of them, the said Surveyors General shall put out such Vnder-Surveyors, and put in such other fit and able person and persons in his
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:169141:6"/> or their rooms from time to time as they shall think fit.</p>
            <p>The said Vnder-Surveyors, so appointed as aforesaid, shall have power to enter into all and every the forfeited Lands aforesaid, lying within such Counties, places and divisions, as they shall be appointed unto, and aswell by the Oaths of Good and Lawfull men, as by all other Lawfull waies and means, to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire and find out all and every the Honours, Baronies, Castles, Mannors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements, Rents, Annuities, Reversions, Remainders, Possessions, and other Hereditaments whatsoever, which late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, or at any time since the twentie third day of <hi>October</hi> in the year one thousand six hundred fourty and one, did belong unto any person or persons whose Lands are forfeited as aforesaid, or to any other person or persons in trust for him, them, or any of them, and the true year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly value thereof, as the same were letten for, or worth to be let, in the year one thousand six hundred and fourty, or at any time before; And also what part of the Premisses are chargeable with any pious and Charitable use or uses; And also to enquire and survey what Timber, Buildings, Open Quaries, and Mines are up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Premisses, and to make true particular Surveys of their proceedings.</p>
            <p>The Surveyors shall also in like manner, and by the like waies and means, examine and find out all such Honours, Castles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, Rents, or Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments belonging unto the Crown in the year
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:169141:7"/> one thousand six hundred and thirty, or any time since, and Survey the same, with all Houses, Edifices, Timber, Woods, Mines, and the appurtenances thereunto belonging, and return the same in distinct surveys by them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, together with the true yearly value ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of in the year one thousand six hundred and fourty.</p>
            <p>They shall also by the like waies and means, examine and find out all Honours, Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, Castles, and Mannors, Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, Rents or other Hereditaments late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly belonging to any Arch-Bishop, Bishops, Deans, Dean and Chapter, or other Officers belonging to that Hierarchy in <hi>Ireland,</hi> in the right of his Arch-Bishoprick, Bishoprick, Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary or office aforesaid, and Survey the same, with all Houses, Edifices, Timber, Woods, Mines, with the appurtenances, and return the same distinctly by themselves, together with the true yearly value, as the same was in the year one thousand six hundred and fourty, which Surveys shall be kept by the Register distinct and apart from the Surveys of the forfeited Lands.</p>
            <p>The said Vnder-Surveyours shall have pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to keep Courts of Survey, and to Call be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them such persons as they conceive best know the forfeited Lands to be admeasu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by them, or the Lands not forfeit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, lying amongst them, or abutting upon them, and to examine them concerning the Meets, Bounds, Rights, Title, Rents, Valuations, of any of the said Lands and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:169141:7"/> Premisses, and, for the more full discoveries of the same, to examine upon Oath all Persons other than such as have interest in, or title to, the Lands in Question, whom they presume can inform them in the Premisses.</p>
            <p>The said Vnder-Surveyours shall return every Survey, assoon as the same is made, to the Surveyours Generals, attested under their hands, and a duplicate thereof in like manner attested to the Register, together with all Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords, Evidences, and writings which shall come to their hands concerning the Premis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses.</p>
            <p>The Surveyours General upon the receipt of any Survey or Certificate from the Vnder-Surveyours, shall peruse them with diligence, and if they find the same to be mistaken or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fective, or any way insufficient to contract upon or otherwise to be disposed of, that then they cause to be transcribed so much of the said Survey as they shall judge to be mistaken, defective, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny waies imperfect, and return the same unto the Respective Vnder-Surveyours, and certifie them the Causes of their exceptions, who shall thereupon forthwith examine the truth thereof, and amend the same, or certifie the cause why they cannot do it.</p>
            <p>The Surveyours General shall have power to Certifie and amend Mistakes, Errors, and other Matters that are not of substance in any of the said Surveys, that the Surveyours General in all Cases where they can (by proof of Witnesses upon Oath (which they have
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:169141:8"/> hereby power to administer) amend any survey without any return of the Surveyors, that then they, by the advice and consent of three of the Commissioners aforementioned for hearing and determining Claims, shall and may a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend the same, which shall be as good and effectual as if the same had been so returned.</p>
            <div type="oath">
               <head>The Oath to be taken by the Surveyors General.</head>
               <p>I <hi>A. B.</hi> do swear that I will, according to my best skill and knowledge, faithfully discharge the duty and trust committed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to me as Surveyor General for <hi>Ireland,</hi> accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Instructions I have received, and shall receive, in that behalf, and that I will not for favour or affection, malice, reward or gift, or hopes of reward or gift, break the same.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="oath">
               <head>The Oath of the Vnder-Surveyors.</head>
               <p>I <hi>A. B.</hi> do swear that I will faithfully and truly, according to my best skill and knowledge, perform the duty and trust of a Surveyor in all such Surveys as I shall be imployed in, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording unto the Instructions which I have received, and such further Instructions as I shall receive, from the Commissioners of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, or Surveyors General, and shall make true Returns thereof unto the Surveyors General, and Register, and shall neither for fear nor favour, malice or reward, or hopes of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, violate the trust reposed in me.</p>
               <p>The Register shall take and have the Custody
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:169141:8"/> and keeping of all Lieger Books, Writings and Evidences which shall belong, or in any wise appertain, unto the Lands, Tenements, and Premisses, which are to be returned unto him by the Surveyors, as also the Duplicates of the Surveys which shall be returned to him, which he shall fairly lay up and keep in good Order, making Catalogues of them in such manner as that any person may come readily to have a view of the same, and the said Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gister hath power to give Copies attested under his hand.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="oath">
               <head>The Oath of the Register.</head>
               <p>I <hi>A.B.</hi> do swear that I will faithfully and truly, according to my best skill and knowledge, execute the Office and Place of Register for the several Lands in <hi>Ireland</hi> forfeited for Treason, and other Lands to be surveyed, according to the trust in me reposed and such Instruc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions as I shall receive in that behalf, and that I will not for fear, favour, malice or reward, or hope of reward violate the said Trust.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="oath">
               <head>The like Oath for the Deputy Register <hi>Mutatis Mutandis.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>For the better keeping and preserving of the Surveys and all such Records and Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings as shall concern the Premisses, You are to appoint some convenient and publique place or house within the City of <hi>Dublin</hi> for the Surveyors General and the Register to keep their said Offices in, as you shall think fit.</p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:169141:9"/>
               <p>The Surveyors General shall have each of them from the date of their Commission the yearly sallary of four hundred pounds, and the Register the yearly sallary of three hundred pounds, the one half whereof to be paid to each of them in ready money quarterly by equal portions out of the Revenue of <hi>Ireland</hi> by your Warrant, the other half in Lands after the same rate as shall be allowed to those who have money due upon publique faith.</p>
               <p>You are hereby impowered to allow unto such Clerks and other Officers as you shall find necessary to be allowed to the said Surveyors General, and Register, for making out, entring or transcribing Surveys, Particulars, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts, Iournal Books, or other service, such Competent and Convenient sallaries, to begin at such time as need shall require, as you shall think meet to be paid quarterly unto them, out of the Publique Revenue of Ireland.</p>
               <p>The Surveyors General, Register, Vnder-Surveyors, Clerks and other Officers being allowed sallaries as aforesaid, shall not take or receive any Fee, Reward, or gratuity, from any person or persons, for or in respect of any thing in relation to his or their office or imploy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment aforesaid, upon pain of forfeiting his or their respective places and offices, and incurring such further punishment as the demerit of his or their offence shall deserve.</p>
               <p>And whereas it is intended that the Adven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turers, Souldiers, and Officers, should be satisfyed, and <hi>Ireland</hi> planted with as much ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pedition as may be, you are to consider, and
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:169141:9"/> advise whether by any other way or means than is before in and by these Instructions prescribed, with less expence, and in a shorter time, a Gross Survey may be taken, of the several Honours, Baronies, Mannors, Lands, or Tenements, so forfeited as aforesaid, so as there may be some certainty what Honours, Baronies, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, are forfeited, and an esti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate made what quantity of Meadow, A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, and Profitable Pasture, and what Woods, Boggs, &amp; Barren Mountains, are belonging to each of them respectively, that thereby way may be made for allotments between the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venturers and the said Souldiers and Officers, and afterwards, upon the Division or Allot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of each persons respective proportion, or in some convenient time after, a more exact Admeasurement may be made. And in case you shall find the same may be effected, you are hereby authorized and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to take such speedy course therein (with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out proceeding by the way of Vnder-Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors herein before prescribed) as you shall judge most expedient and effectual to lessen the charge, and shorten the Work. And you are impowered to imploy therein, such, and so ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny persons, and to allow them such Sallaries, or recompence, to be paid in such manner, and to give them Orders and Instructions to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed therein by such waies and means as you shall think fit. And you are to cause such gross Surveys of each particular Honour, Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nie, Mannor, Lands, or Tenements, and of the Quantity and Number of Acres of Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:169141:10"/> Arable, and Profitable Pasture, by e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stimation (together with the Woods, Boggs, and Barren Mountains) to each of them re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spectively (or to any two or more of them adjoining or lying together) belonging, to be taken, and returned in writing, under the hands of such persons as aforesaid, to the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors General, and a Duplicate thereof to the Register for the said Lands, with all possi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble expedition.</p>
               <p>You shall give direction to the Register a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, that assoon as any such Survey or esti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate shall be transmitted unto him, he draw out of the same an Abstract, how many Acres of Meadow, Arable, and Profitable Pasture, is in such survey or estimate mentioned to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long to such Honour, Barony, Mannor, or Tenement, so as an exact and perfect Abstract of all such of the said forfeited Lands as are of that Condition within the said Ten Counties, and also in the County of <hi>Lowth,</hi> may, immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately upon the return of the said Surveys or esti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mates of the Premisses in the said Eleven Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, be sent over unto <hi>Mr. Methusulah Turner, Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Hamond,</hi> and others, appointed Committee to sit at <hi>Grocers Hall,</hi> under your hands and seals.</p>
               <p>You shall observe and execute such further Instructions in and about the Premisses, as you shall from time to time receive from the present Council of State (untill the meeting of the Supreme Authority of this Nation) and after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards from the said Supreme Authority, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:169141:10"/> authorized by them on that behalf.</p>
               <p>Whereas an Act of Parliament was made the twelfth day of <hi>August</hi> 1652. entituled, <hi>An Act for the settling of Ireland,</hi> whereby it is declared, that all and every person and persons of the <hi>Irish</hi> Nation comprehended in any of the Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications in that Act contained, should be ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to the Penalties and Forfeitures therein mentioned and contained, or be made capable of the Mercy and Pardon therein extended respectively, as is expressed and declared in the said Act and Qualifications, to the end that no person or persons who is not comprehended within the said Qualifications, or any of them, may re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive prejudice in his Lands or Estate, and that every person to whom it doth belong, may en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy the mercy and favour intended unto him by the said Act, you are hereby authorized to receive, hear, and finally determine, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints and Claims of all and every such per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son and persons as shall before or within such time as you shall appoint, not exceeding fourty days at the most after his or their Lands shall be surveyed as aforesaid, addresse himself, or them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, unto you for relief therein, for which purpose you are hereby authorized and impow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to examine Witnesses upon oath for charging or cleering such person or persons; And you shall thereupon transmit a Copy of such your determination, unto the Register for the said Lands, to be by him entred into a Book for that purpose, according to which determination so cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified, the Lands of such person or persons shall be either discharged, or disposed of as other for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited Lands.</p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:169141:11"/>
               <p>Provided that nothing herein contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed shall extend to the surveying, admea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>surement, or setting forth any of the Honours, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, or Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments in <hi>Ireland,</hi> given, or granted since the first day of <hi>November</hi> in the year 1641. by any Act, Ordinance, or Order of Parliament, to any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or persons whatsoever, or unto their Heirs or Assigns, nor to the Mannour of <hi>Blarny</hi> in the County of <hi>Cork,</hi> with the Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments thereunto belonging.</p>
               <p>And whereas for the lessning of the Charge of the Commonwealth, and easing of the Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants of <hi>Ireland,</hi> It is resolved, That part of the present Army in <hi>Ireland</hi> be forthwith disbanded, &amp; forasmuch as the surveying and dividing the ten Counties aforesaid, and the determining the Lots between the Adventurers and Souldiers, touching the same, must necessarily be perfe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted before the Souldiers can receive satisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of their Arrears, out of any of the forfeited Lands in those Counties, which will unavoid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably require so much time as would be an occasion of a great Charge to the Common-Wealth, in case such disbanding should be so long delayed, And it being evident, that if the Soul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers should be disbanded before they can receive satisfaction for their Arrears, they would be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed to great extremity, if not to utter ruin; To the end therefore such Officers and Soul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers as shall be so disbanded, may, immediatly upon their disbanding, receive such proportions of Land, as may satisfy the Arrears grown due unto them since the fift of <hi>June</hi> 1649. and
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:169141:11"/> be put into a way of planting, and the better enabled to subsist, You are hereby authorized and impower'd, out of such of the forfeited Lands (as are not already disposed of by any Act, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance, or Order of Parliament) lying within any such five Counties in <hi>Jreland,</hi> as you shall think fit (other than the Counties of <hi>Dublin, Kil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dare,</hi> and <hi>Caterlaugh,</hi> in the Province of <hi>Lemster;</hi> and <hi>Cork</hi> in the Province of <hi>Munster,</hi> and other than the eleven Counties herein by name appointed to be surveyed) to set forth, or cause to be set forth, unto each of the Officers and Souldiers to be disbanded as aforesaid (clear of all such claims and titles, provided for in the foregoing Instructions) Proportions of profitable Land, by estimation, or grosse survey of the number of Acres, as shall be sufficient to satisfy the Arrears due as aforesaid, to such Officer and Souldier respectively, at the values and rates hereafter mentioned, that is to say, For one thousand Acres in <hi>Vlster,</hi> two hundred pounds; For one thousand Acres in <hi>Munster,</hi> four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and fifty pounds; And for one thousand Acres in <hi>Lemster,</hi> six hundred pounds, All according to <hi>Jrish</hi> measure; which estimate, or grosse survey, You shall cause to be put in Writing, and therein to be mentioned aswell the sum of Money due to such Officer and Soul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dier respectively for his Arrears, as the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of Acres Arable, Meadow, and Profi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Pasture, set forth unto him for his said Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rears, by estimation as aforesaid, so deciphered and distinguished by the Quantities, Qualities, Names, Situation, Baronie, Mannor, or Parish, as aforesaid, and shall cause such sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:169141:12"/> to be sent unto the Register for the said Lands, to be safely kept as a Record, to the end, that in case (upon a more exact survey and admeasurement to be made on the behalf of the State, within five years next after such setting forth as aforesaid respectively) it shall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear that the Premisses expressed in such sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey, and enjoyed by vertue thereof, do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain a greater number of Acres than is men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in such estimate or grosse Survey, the same may be restored back for the use of the Commonwealth, unlesse such per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons shall purchase the same in such manner as shall be hereafter declared. Provided never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theless, That if any Officer or Souldier so to be disbanded, holdeth any Custodium in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of the said five Counties, or in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of <hi>Dublin, Kildare, Caterlaugh,</hi> and <hi>Cork</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, and is there seated, and desires to retain the same, You are hereby impower<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and authorized to contract with such Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer and Officers, Souldier and Souldiers, for Houses and Lands with the appurtenances contained in such Custodium, at such rates and values as you shall think fit, and for the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage of the Commonwealth, (having a due respect therein to the charge which hath been laid out, by such Officer or Souldier, in repay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring or building, upon the premisses) and to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the moneys due for such Arrears as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, unto such Officer or Souldier in payment of the purchase money for the same, and in case the Purchase shall amount to more than the Arrears so due to such Officer or Souldier, then such remainder of the Purchase money shall
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:169141:12"/> be paid in to the Publique Treasurie of <hi>Ireland,</hi> for the use of the Commonwealth, and that such Officer and Officers, Souldier and Souldiers, shall by force thereof hold and enjoy the same according to such contract, which, together with the Survey of the Premisses so contracted for, You shall cause to be returned to the said Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster, to be safely kept with the rest of the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veys.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="order_to_print">
            <head>
               <hi>Iune</hi> 29. 1653.</head>
            <p>At the Council of State at White-Hall, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered, That this Commission and Instructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons be forthwith Printed and Published.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>John Thurloe</hi> Secr.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>